comet.co.uk 2012-10-14

# 

## Privacy Policy

Comet Group Ltd ("Comet", "us", "we") takes the protection of your online privacy seriously and this Privacy Policy sets out how we use and protect any personal information we obtain from dealings which arise from you using this website. Comet is not responsible for the privacy practices of any websites which may be linked from the Comet website, so please check separately their privacy policies. 

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time by updating this page so please check our Privacy Policy for any changes when you revisit our website. This Privacy Policy is effective from December 2011.

### What personal information do we collect?

We ask for your personal information when you make a purchase in store, register with MyComet, sign up for promotions, offers or competitions, or to receive news, or when you fill in the personal details section of 'Your Basket' to make a purchase. Depending on which of these services you use, we may collect: 

  * your name and contact information including postal address, e-mail address and telephone number, even if you do not complete your purchase;
  * details of any purchase orders that you place through the website, and any details we need for delivery, installation, appliance disposal, product service plan or product servicing as applicable;
  * card payment details if making a purchase;
  * details you provide when you contact us or make enquiries either generally or about any purchases you make with us; 
  * details of your visits to the website and the resources that you access; and 
  * information you provide if you report a problem with our website;

Even if you do not use these services, or for example, do not proceed with a purchase, we will still gather any personal details entered and information about your activity on the website to understand what parts of the website and what products you are interested in, so that we can improve our website and tailor our services to you. Further details are in the Cookies section of this Privacy Policy. 

### What we do with the personal information we collect?

Depending on how you engage with us, we may use your information:

  * to facilitate your use of this website and the services available through it;
  * when you purchase from us, to process your order, collect payment, enable you to track you order online, arrange delivery and for other purchase related services such as installation, disposal of your old appliance (as relevant), and product warranty (this may include contacting you by telephone, email or SMS to arrange, confirm or upgrade your delivery, installation or appliance disposal) and for ongoing customer service dealings including any faults or repairs or refunds; 
  * for internal accounting and regulatory purposes;
  * for statistical analysis to assess our business performance and to improve our products and services;
  * to improve and personalise your experience when you visit the website (See Cookies), and to keep you informed about other products and services you might be interested in (See Keeping You Informed); and
  * to ask you from time to time if you would like to provide feedback on or participate in market research on our products and services. You do not have to participate in these if you do not wish.

### Who do we share it with?

Please note that Comet is legally required to notify the TV Licensing Authority of any purchase you make of television receiving equipment. Please see [www.tvlicensing.co.uk](http://www.tvlicensing.co.uk/) for more details. 

If you take out an additional service plan with your purchase, Comet will share limited personal information with the service plan provider.

Comet may also disclose your personal information:

  * if we use authorised service providers to perform certain services on our behalf, for example this might include providing IT support and maintenance, website hosting services, our direct marketing programme and for online payment services. We do not permit our service providers to share or to use such information for any other purpose and they are under strict obligations to keep your information secure; 
  * Trusted third party suppliers providing relevant products and services related to your Comet purchases (see Keeping You Informed)
  * to the police, regulators, law enforcement or other government agency where the law requires this, where appropriate to prevent or detect criminal activity, or in connection with product safety, and otherwise to relevant third parties to protect Comet, its business, staff and customers; and 
  * to prospective or actual buyers in the event that Comet sells any of its business or assets so help ensure continuity of your customer relationship.

### Keeping You Informed

We may from time to time contact or update you about products, services or offers that may be relevant to you.

This may include delivery, installation and appliance disposal options, and extended warranties, and other products and services related to your Comet purchases, some of which are provided by Comet and some by our trusted partners to whom we may pass on your details. 

We or they may contact you about these by telephone, mail, email and SMS, using the contact details you provide and update us with, which we obtain or update with you in our dealings, or which we obtain or update from external sources. This may include telephone numbers which are registered by you or others with the Telephone Preference Service unless you have told us directly that you do not wish to be contacted for this purpose on a particular telephone number. _By providing your details through the website, you are agreeing to this._

If you don't want to be contacted by post or telephone you can email us at [dataremoval@comet.co.uk](mailto:dataremoval@comet.co.uk) or write to us at the address in Your Rights. If you do so, please bear with us for a short time whilst we adjust our records. This usually takes up to 28 days but we try to do it sooner. 

If you don't want to be contacted by email, please change from the 'yes' to the 'no' options when you first give your details online. If you choose 'yes' you can still change your mind later, Comet's marketing emails contain an easy means for you to unsubscribe. 

Please note that Comet would not necessarily remove all your details from its records but would note and respect your changed marketing preferences.

### Security and Storage

Whilst we have policies, rules and measures in place and try to take all reasonable steps to safeguard your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you provide online. 

## What are cookies?

Cookies are small files that are downloaded on to your computer when you visit a website and they typically hold bits of information like the site name and unique used ID. They are simply text files and they are not programs. These small bits of information can then be accessed by your browser and allows it to be recognised by a website if you decide to return. The information that cookies contain help to make your browsing experience smoother, for example they enable you to store items in your basket, adding each item as you click "add to basket" and even to tailor the things that you see on a website to your personal preferences. Cookies do not harm your computer and are not "programs". 

Comet.co.uk uses cookies to remember you when you return to our website and to allow you to add products to your basket. If you do not want to have cookies enabled then you can browse Comet.co.uk but you will not be able to purchase products. We do not store any personal information such as your credit card details but do use the information to improve your experience with us and make your time on Comet.co.uk run more smoothly. 

**3rd Party Cookies**  
In addition to the cookies that we use, we work with a number of trusted 3rd Parties to help improve the level of the online service we offer. They will also place cookies on your computer, these are described in the table below. A number of these cookies are used to provide banner advertisements for Comet when you visit some other websites. The cookies are designed to provide you with relevant advertising based on the products you have recently viewed on our website. Again these do not contain any personally identifiable information, but if you would like to opt out of these marketing cookies please click here to be taken to an independent website which will help you identify and manage cookies of this nature that have been stored on your computer by our and other businesses’ websites. 

## Are there different types of cookies? 

**Session, or transient cookies**  
Cookies that are stored in the computer's memory only during a user's browsing session and are automatically deleted from the user's computer when the browser is closed. 

These cookies usually store a session ID that is not personally identifiable to users, allowing the user to move from page to page without having to log-in repeatedly. They are widely used by commercial web sites (for example, to keep track of items that a consumer has added to a shopping cart).

Session cookies are never written on the hard drive and they do not collect any information from the user's computer. Session cookies expire at the end of the user's browser session and can also become no longer accessible after the session has been inactive for a specified length of time, usually 20 minutes.

**Permanent, persistent, or stored cookies**  
Cookies that are stored on the user's computer and are not deleted when the browser is closed. Permanent cookies can retain user preferences for a particular web site, allowing those preferences to be used in future browsing sessions. 

Permanent cookies can be used to identify individual users, so they may be used by web sites to analyse users' surfing behaviour within the web site. These cookies can also be used to provide information about numbers of visitors, the average time spent on a particular page and generally the performance of the web site. They are usually configured to keep track of users for a prolonged period of time, in some cases many years into the future.

**Flash cookies**  
If you have Adobe Flash installed on your computer (most computers do), small files may be stored on your computer by websites that contain Flash media, such as video clips. These files are known as Local Shared Objects (LSOs) or Flash cookies. They can be used for the same purposes as regular cookies (properly called HTTP cookies). 

Flash cookies can also back up the data that is stored in a regular cookie. When you delete cookies using your browser controls, your Flash cookies are not affected. So a website that served a cookie to you may recognise you on your next visit if it backed up its now-deleted cookie data to a Flash cookie.
